

William Barbosa

PhD in Applied Economics

- ▶ São Paulo, Brazil
- Brazilian
- Single

Skills

R	9+ yrs.
LaTex	9+ yrs.
QGIS	10+ yrs.
Rmarkdown	5+ yrs.
SQL	5+ yrs.
Shiny App	4+ yrs.
Python	4+ yrs.
Quarto	2+ yrs.
Web Scraping	5+ yrs.
Julia	2+ yrs.

Tools

- ▶ Git
- RStudio
- VS Code
- QGIS

Summary

PhD in Applied Economics from ESALQ/USP. Master in Economics from the Federal University of Santa Maria - RS. Specialist in Agribusiness from the University of São Paulo. He holds a degree in Economic Sciences from the State University of Ponta Grossa - UEPG (2014). Specialized in time series analysis; spatial econometrics; panel data; Logit and Probit models. He works mainly in areas related to regional economics and applied economics. Currently the line of research involves the areas of applied economics, focusing on quantitative models, Machine Learning and Text Mining. Expert in Big Data, programming for data analysis and modeling in R, Python and Stata.

Experience

Senior Risk Methodology Analyst

02/2020 - Present

ERM Forecasting - Santander Brazil

Development of stress test models to predict PD and LGD; Credit risk rating and score.

Advising professor at the MBA in Data Science and Analytics

09/2021 - Present

Programa de Educação Continuada em Economia e Gestão de Empresas - PECEGE

Supervising professor of course completion work lato sensu level

Advising professor at the MBA in Business management

01/2019 - 09/2022

Programa de Educação Continuada em Economia e Gestão de Empresas - PECEGE

Supervising professor of course completion work lato sensu level

Advising professor at the MBA in Agribusiness

01/2019 - 09/2022

Programa de Educação Continuada em Economia e Gestão de Empresas - PECEGE

Supervising professor of course completion work lato sensu level

External consultant and reviewer of cash flow calculations economic viability and financial calculations of courses in Business management / Agribusiness

01/2019 - 09/2022

Programa de Educação Continuada em Economia e Gestão de Empresas - PECEGE

Supervising professor of course completion work lato sensu level

- Stata
- Terminal

Contact

- São Paulo, Brazil
- *→* +55 42 99946 7555
- williambarbosa@alumni.usp.br
- William Barbosa

Education

See my Lattes profile for more academic information.

PhD in Applied Economics

02/2017 - 04/2021

University of São Paulo - Escola Superior de Agricultura 'Luiz de Queiroz' - USP/ESALQ

Thesis: Climate change in agriculture and internal migration in Brazil

Msc in Master in Economics and Development

02/2015 - 02/2017

Federal University of Santa Maria - UFSM/RS

Migrations In Brazil: An Application Of The Gravity Model With Panel Data (2002-2015)

MBA in Data Science and Analytics

07/2021 - 06/2023

Programa de Educação Continuada em Economia e Gestão de Empresas - PECEGE

Spatial analysis of the deforestation rate in the Cerrado Biome 1985-2017

MBA in Agribusiness

07/2019 - 06/2021

Programa de Educação Continuada em Economia e Gestão de Empresas - PECEGE

Analysis of deforestation and agricultural growth in the municipalities of MATOPIBA 2006-2017

Degree in Economic

02/2011 - 12/2014

State University of Ponta Grossa - UEPG/PR

Empirical Analysis of the Evidence of Deindustrialization in the State of Paraná in the Period from 1996 to 2012